Finding Aid for Rinsey family papers, 1856-1950
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Rinsey family papers 1856-1950 1913-1928
Rinsey family.
1 linear foot
861000 Aa 2
Ann Arbor, Michigan family, proprietors of Rinsey & Seabolt grocery store. Papers of David Rinsey, Ann Arbor, Michigan, grocer; also papers of his son George, a bank teller, and of George's wife, Ina Alexander Rinsey; including correspondence, legal documents, and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by the estate of Ina Alexander Rinsey (donor no. 7263 ) and came to the library in 1985.
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Rinsey family, headed by David Rinsey, were proprietors of Rinsey & Seabolt grocery store of Ann Arbor, Michigan. His son George Rinsey was a bank teller.
The collection includes correspondence and legal documents of David Rinsey, his son George, and of George's wife, Ina Alexander Rinsey. There are also photographs and photograph albums of the Rinsey family's home and place of business in Ann Arbor. The photographs consists of both formal and informal portraits; interior and exterior photos of their homes on North Division St., Ann Arbor, Michigan; interior and exterior photos of Rinsey & Seabolt grocery on E. Washington St.; and photographs of family events and activities.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Dwellings.; Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Alexander family.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Buildings.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Churches.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Dwellings.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Grocery stores.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Streets.; Buildings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Children.; Churches--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Clothing and dress.; Dwellings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Dwellings--Ohio.; Families.; Fathers and children.; Florida.; Funeral rites and ceremonies.; Grocery stores--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Interiors.; Mackinac Island (Mich.); Nuns.; Rinsey, Ina Alexander.; Rinsey family.; St. Thomas the Apostle Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Streets--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Weddings.
Contributors:
Rinsey, David, b. 1838.; Rinsey, George, 1881-; Rinsey, Ina Alexander.
Genre Terms:
Albums.; Photographs.
- Correspondence
  - 1913-1927 (Box 1)
  - 1928 (Box 1)
  - 1929 (Box 1)
  - 1930-1948 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous and Undated material (Box 1)
  - Album of letters to Theodore Alexander upon death of his wife, 1906 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1 folder and 1 album (Box 1)
  - Legal Documents Land Contracts Mortgages Stock Certificates Warranty Deeds Wills Miscellaneous (Box 1)
    (include specifications for 402 N. Division home)
- Photographs
  - Portraits, 3 envelopes (Box 1)
  - Informal photos of family members and others (Box 1)
  - David Rinsey home, 402 N. Division, Ann Arbor (Box 1)
    (include informal photos of Rinsey children by house)
  - George Rinsey home, 406 N. Division (Box 1)
  - Rinsey property, 4th and Division (Box 1)
    (now Embassy Hotel)
  - Rinsey store, interior (Washington Street), ca. 1910s (Box 1)
  - Bowling Green, Ohio, home (Box 1)
  - Family albums, 3 volumes (Box 1)
    (one album includes views of home, St. Thomas Church in Ann Arbor, and vacation photos)